fanniemae.com 2011-12-07

# Privacy Statement | Fannie Mae

Fannie Mae respects your concerns about privacy and values its relationship with you. This Online Privacy Notice applies to the following Fannie Mae Web sites (our "Sites")

  * **FannieMae.com**
  * **eFannieMae.com**
  * **KnowYourOptions.com**
  * **HomePath.com**

This Online Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we collect on our Sites, how we use the information, with whom we share the information, and the choices you can make about our use of the information. We also describe the measures we take to protect the security of the information and how you can contact us about our privacy practices.

This Online Privacy Notice does not apply to information provided to us by business entities or individuals acting in a professional capacity using our technology applications, even if launched through eFannieMae.com. If you use any of our technology applications in the course of your business with us, information you submit will be governed by our agreement with you governing the use of that application. We will only use and disclose such information in accordance with all applicable laws.

### Information We Collect

We may obtain certain personal information (such as name and other contact details) through our Sites. Here are the most common types of information:

  * Contact information (such as name, postal address, email address, telephone number and fax number); 
  * login and access credentials (such as username and password); 
  * information about your property or mortgage loan; 
  * age and gender; 
  * real estate license number; and 
  * responses to brief online surveys 
  * comments you submit through our Sites. 

We offer visitors to our Sites various services, which we may change from time to time. We may ask you to submit certain personal information so we can provide you with these services.

When you visit our Sites, information may be collected through automated technologies such as cookies, web server logs and web beacons. A "cookie" is a file that Web sites send to a visitor's computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify the visitor's browser or to store information or settings in the browser. A "web beacon," also known as an Internet tag, pixel tag or clear GIF, links web pages to web servers and their cookies and may be used to transmit information collected through cookies back to a web server. The information collected using these tools may include your IP address, browser characteristics, operating system, the address of the web page that referred you to our Site, dates and times of Site visits, the language your system uses, and the country and time zone in which your device is located. These technologies permit the collection of "clickstream data," which may include a log of content you access while browsing a website.

On some of our Sites, we also use third-party web analytics services, such as Omniture, ForSee and Google Analytics. These services may rely upon technologies such as cookies, web server logs and web beacons to help us analyze how visitors reach and interact with our Sites. The information collected through these means (including IP address) is disclosed to or collected directly by these service providers. To learn more about Omniture's collection and analysis of information by automated means, including how to opt out, **[click here](http://www.omniture.com/en/privacy/product)**. To learn more about Google's collection and analysis of information by automated means, including how to opt out, **[click here](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html)**. To learn more about ForSee's collection and analysis of information by automated means, including how to opt out, **[click here](http://www.foreseeresults.com/products/)**.

### How We Use The Information We Collect

We may use the information we collect to:

  * Verify your identity; 
  * provide, administer and communicate with you about products, services, and events; 
  * create, administer and communicate with you about your online account or subscription; 
  * process, evaluate and respond to your requests, inquiries and applications; 
  * provide and administer communications tools available through our sites, such as tools for submitting online offers to purchase homes owned by Fannie Mae; 
  * operate, evaluate and improve our business (including developing new products and services; managing our communications; performing market research; managing our advertising and marketing; analyzing our products, services and our sites; administering our sites; and performing accounting, auditing, billing, reconciliation and collection activities); 
  * protect against and prevent fraud, unauthorized activity, claims and other liabilities; and 
  * comply with and enforce applicable legal requirements, industry standards and our policies and terms of use 

We also may use the information in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection.

### Sharing of Information

We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal information we collect on our Sites, except as described here. We may share the information with our service providers who perform services on our behalf. These service providers are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements. We may also provide personal information to third parties such as technology providers to enable such third parties to perform business, professional and technical support functions for us, our Sites or for you. On certain Sites, we provide tools to allow real estate agents to communicate with each other to negotiate transactions. In the course of these communications, they may use our tools to share personal information about the parties they represent.

In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal process (such as a court order), (ii) in response to a request by law enforcement authorities or regulatory agencies, or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity. We also reserve the right to transfer personal information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such an event occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided to us on our Sites in a manner that is consistent with this Online Privacy Notice.

### Your Rights and Choices

We offer you certain choices about how we communicate with you and what information we collect from you. Some of our Sites provide features that allow you to (i) access and update personal information you have provided there or (ii) register your communications preferences, such as by telling us not to send you marketing materials. You also may contact us as described in the How To Contact Us section below to update your preferences, ask us to remove your information from our mailing lists or submit other requests. Business contacts may be required to receive certain information in the course of doing business with Fannie Mae. **Click here** for your options regarding third parties' automated collection of information on our Sites.

### How We Protect Personal Information

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information we collect on our Sites against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use.

### Links to Other Web site and Embedded Content

Our Sites may provide links to other Web site or present content from other Web site for your convenience and information. These Web sites may operate independently from Fannie Mae. The Web sites may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked Web site or pages containing content hosted by other Web sites. To the extent such Web sites are not owned or controlled by Fannie Mae, we are not responsible for the Web site's content, any use of the Web site, or the privacy practices of the Web site.

### Updates to Our Online Privacy Notice

This Online Privacy Notice may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal information practices. We will post a prominent notice on our Sites to notify you of any significant changes to this Online Privacy Notice, indicate when it was most recently updated and its effective date. Unless otherwise stated, changes in our personal information practices are immediately applicable to you upon publication of the revised Online Privacy Notice.

### How to Contact Us

If you have any questions or comments about this Online Privacy Notice, please:

Write to:  
Fannie Mae   
3900 Wisconsin Ave., NW   
Washington, DC 20016

E-mail:
